[
    {
        "question": "1. What is an IPv4 address? What are the different classes of IPv4?",
        "answer": "An IP address is a 32-bit dynamic address of a node in the network. An IPv4 address has 4 octets of 8-bit each with each number with a value up to 255. IPv4 classes are differentiated based on the number of hosts it supports on the network. There are five types of IPv4 classes and are based on the first octet of IP addresses which are classified as Class A, B, C, D, or E. IPv4 Class IPv4 Start Address IPv4 End Address Usage\nA 0.0.0.0 127.255.255.255 Used for Large Network\nB 128.0.0.0 191.255.255.255 Used for Medium Size Network\nC 192.0.0.0 223.255.255.255 Used for Local Area Network\nD 224.0.0.0 239.255.255.255 Reserved for Multicasting\nE 240.0.0.0 255.255.255.254 Study and R&D IPv4 Class IPv4 Start Address IPv4 End Address Usage\nA 0.0.0.0 127.255.255.255 Used for Large Network\nB 128.0.0.0 191.255.255.255 Used for Medium Size Network\nC 192.0.0.0 223.255.255.255 Used for Local Area Network\nD 224.0.0.0 239.255.255.255 Reserved for Multicasting\nE 240.0.0.0 255.255.255.254 Study and R&D IPv4 Class IPv4 Start Address IPv4 End Address Usage IPv4 Class IPv4 Start Address IPv4 End Address Usage IPv4 Class IPv4 Start Address IPv4 End Address Usage A 0.0.0.0 127.255.255.255 Used for Large Network\nB 128.0.0.0 191.255.255.255 Used for Medium Size Network\nC 192.0.0.0 223.255.255.255 Used for Local Area Network\nD 224.0.0.0 239.255.255.255 Reserved for Multicasting\nE 240.0.0.0 255.255.255.254 Study and R&D A 0.0.0.0 127.255.255.255 Used for Large Network A 0.0.0.0 127.255.255.255 Used for Large Network B 128.0.0.0 191.255.255.255 Used for Medium Size Network B 128.0.0.0 191.255.255.255 Used for Medium Size Network C 192.0.0.0 223.255.255.255 Used for Local Area Network C 192.0.0.0 223.255.255.255 Used for Local Area Network D 224.0.0.0 239.255.255.255 Reserved for Multicasting D 224.0.0.0 239.255.255.255 Reserved for Multicasting E 240.0.0.0 255.255.255.254 Study and R&D E 240.0.0.0 255.255.255.254 Study and R&D  Also, check out Scaler topics' Free Computer Networks course with certification to learn the fundamentals of computer networking. Computer Networks Computer Networks",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Explain different types of networks.",
        "answer": "Below are few types of networks: Type Description\nPAN (Personal Area Network) Let devices connect and communicate over the range of a person. E.g. connecting Bluetooth devices.\nLAN (Local Area Network) It is a privately owned network that operates within and nearby a single building like a home, office, or factory\nMAN (Metropolitan Area Network) It connects and covers the whole city. E.g. TV Cable connection over the city\nWAN (Wide Area Network) It spans a large geographical area, often a country or continent. The Internet is the largest WAN\nGAN (Global Area Network) It is also known as the Internet which connects the globe using satellites. The Internet is also called the Network of WANs. Type Description\nPAN (Personal Area Network) Let devices connect and communicate over the range of a person. E.g. connecting Bluetooth devices.\nLAN (Local Area Network) It is a privately owned network that operates within and nearby a single building like a home, office, or factory\nMAN (Metropolitan Area Network) It connects and covers the whole city. E.g. TV Cable connection over the city\nWAN (Wide Area Network) It spans a large geographical area, often a country or continent. The Internet is the largest WAN\nGAN (Global Area Network) It is also known as the Internet which connects the globe using satellites. The Internet is also called the Network of WANs. Type Description Type Description Type Description PAN (Personal Area Network) Let devices connect and communicate over the range of a person. E.g. connecting Bluetooth devices.\nLAN (Local Area Network) It is a privately owned network that operates within and nearby a single building like a home, office, or factory\nMAN (Metropolitan Area Network) It connects and covers the whole city. E.g. TV Cable connection over the city\nWAN (Wide Area Network) It spans a large geographical area, often a country or continent. The Internet is the largest WAN\nGAN (Global Area Network) It is also known as the Internet which connects the globe using satellites. The Internet is also called the Network of WANs. PAN (Personal Area Network) Let devices connect and communicate over the range of a person. E.g. connecting Bluetooth devices. PAN (Personal Area Network) Let devices connect and communicate over the range of a person. E.g. connecting Bluetooth devices. LAN (Local Area Network) It is a privately owned network that operates within and nearby a single building like a home, office, or factory LAN (Local Area Network) It is a privately owned network that operates within and nearby a single building like a home, office, or factory MAN (Metropolitan Area Network) It connects and covers the whole city. E.g. TV Cable connection over the city MAN (Metropolitan Area Network) It connects and covers the whole city. E.g. TV Cable connection over the city WAN (Wide Area Network) It spans a large geographical area, often a country or continent. The Internet is the largest WAN WAN (Wide Area Network) It spans a large geographical area, often a country or continent. The Internet is the largest WAN GAN (Global Area Network) It is also known as the Internet which connects the globe using satellites. The Internet is also called the Network of WANs. GAN (Global Area Network) It is also known as the Internet which connects the globe using satellites. The Internet is also called the Network of WANs.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Explain LAN (Local Area Network)",
        "answer": "LANs are widely used to connect computers/laptops and consumer electronics which enables them to share resources (e.g., printers, fax machines) and exchange information. When LANs are used by companies or organizations, they are called enterprise networks. There are two different types of LAN networks i.e. wireless LAN (no wires involved achieved using Wi-Fi) and wired LAN (achieved using LAN cable). Wireless LANs are very popular these days for places where installing wire is difficult. The below diagrams explain both wireless and wired LAN. enterprise networks LAN (Local Area Network)  LAN (Local Area Network)",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Tell me something about VPN (Virtual Private Network)",
        "answer": "VPN or the Virtual Private Network is a private WAN (Wide Area Network) built on the internet. It allows the creation of a secured tunnel (protected network) between different networks using the internet (public network). By using the VPN, a client can connect to the organization’s network remotely. The below diagram shows an organizational WAN network over Australia created using VPN: VPN (Virtual Private Network)  VPN (Virtual Private Network)",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the advantages of using a VPN?",
        "answer": "Below are few advantages of using VPN: VPN is used to connect offices in different geographical locations remotely and is cheaper when compared to WAN connections.\nVPN is used for secure transactions and confidential data transfer between multiple offices located in different geographical locations.\nVPN keeps an organization’s information secured against any potential threats or intrusions by using virtualization.\nVPN encrypts the internet traffic and disguises the online identity. VPN is used to connect offices in different geographical locations remotely and is cheaper when compared to WAN connections. VPN is used for secure transactions and confidential data transfer between multiple offices located in different geographical locations. VPN keeps an organization’s information secured against any potential threats or intrusions by using virtualization. VPN encrypts the internet traffic and disguises the online identity.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are the different types of VPN?",
        "answer": "Few types of VPN are: Access VPN: Access VPN is used to provide connectivity to remote mobile users and telecommuters. It serves as an alternative to dial-up connections or ISDN (Integrated Services Digital Network) connections. It is a low-cost solution and provides a wide range of connectivity.\nSite-to-Site VPN: A Site-to-Site or Router-to-Router VPN is commonly used in large companies having branches in different locations to connect the network of one office to another in different locations. There are 2 sub-categories as mentioned below:\nIntranet VPN: Intranet VPN is useful for connecting remote offices in different geographical locations using shared infrastructure (internet connectivity and servers) with the same accessibility policies as a private WAN (wide area network).\nExtranet VPN: Extranet VPN uses shared infrastructure over an intranet, suppliers, customers, partners, and other entities and connects them using dedicated connections. Access VPN: Access VPN is used to provide connectivity to remote mobile users and telecommuters. It serves as an alternative to dial-up connections or ISDN (Integrated Services Digital Network) connections. It is a low-cost solution and provides a wide range of connectivity. Access VPN: Site-to-Site VPN: A Site-to-Site or Router-to-Router VPN is commonly used in large companies having branches in different locations to connect the network of one office to another in different locations. There are 2 sub-categories as mentioned below: Site-to-Site VPN: Intranet VPN: Intranet VPN is useful for connecting remote offices in different geographical locations using shared infrastructure (internet connectivity and servers) with the same accessibility policies as a private WAN (wide area network). Intranet VPN: Extranet VPN: Extranet VPN uses shared infrastructure over an intranet, suppliers, customers, partners, and other entities and connects them using dedicated connections. Extranet VPN:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are nodes and links?",
        "answer": "Node: Any communicating device in a network is called a Node. Node is the point of intersection in a network. It can send/receive data and information within a network. Examples of the node can be computers, laptops, printers, servers, modems, etc. Node: Link: A link or edge refers to the connectivity between two nodes in the network. It includes the type of connectivity (wired or wireless) between the nodes and protocols used for one node to be able to communicate with the other. Link: Nodes and Links  Nodes and Links",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is the network topology?",
        "answer": "Network topology is a physical layout of the network, connecting the different nodes using the links. It depicts the connectivity between the computers, devices, cables, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Define different types of network topology",
        "answer": "The different types of network topology are given below: Bus Topology: Bus Topology: Bus Topology  Bus Topology All the nodes are connected using the central link known as the bus.\nIt is useful to connect a smaller number of devices.\nIf the main cable gets damaged, it will damage the whole network. All the nodes are connected using the central link known as the bus. It is useful to connect a smaller number of devices. If the main cable gets damaged, it will damage the whole network. Star Topology: Star Topology: Star Topology  Star Topology All the nodes are connected to one single node known as the central node.\nIt is more robust.\nIf the central node fails the complete network is damaged.\nEasy to troubleshoot.\nMainly used in home and office networks. All the nodes are connected to one single node known as the central node. It is more robust. If the central node fails the complete network is damaged. Easy to troubleshoot. Mainly used in home and office networks. Ring Topology: Ring Topology: Ring Topology  Ring Topology Each node is connected to exactly two nodes forming a ring structure\nIf one of the nodes are damaged, it will damage the whole network\nIt is used very rarely as it is expensive and hard to install and manage Each node is connected to exactly two nodes forming a ring structure If one of the nodes are damaged, it will damage the whole network It is used very rarely as it is expensive and hard to install and manage Mesh Topology: Mesh Topology: Mesh Topology  Mesh Topology Each node is connected to one or many nodes.\nIt is robust as failure in one link only disconnects that node.\nIt is rarely used and installation and management are difficult. Each node is connected to one or many nodes. It is robust as failure in one link only disconnects that node. It is rarely used and installation and management are difficult. Tree Topology: Tree Topology: Tree Topology  Tree Topology A combination of star and bus topology also know as an extended bus topology.\nAll the smaller star networks are connected to a single bus.\nIf the main bus fails, the whole network is damaged. A combination of star and bus topology also know as an extended bus topology. All the smaller star networks are connected to a single bus. If the main bus fails, the whole network is damaged. Hybrid: Hybrid: It is a combination of different topologies to form a new topology.\nIt helps to ignore the drawback of a particular topology and helps to pick the strengths from other. It is a combination of different topologies to form a new topology. It helps to ignore the drawback of a particular topology and helps to pick the strengths from other.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. How are Network types classified?",
        "answer": "Network types can be classified and divided based on the area of distribution of the network. The below diagram would help to understand the same: Network Types  Network Types",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are Private and Special IP addresses?",
        "answer": "Private Address: For each class, there are specific IPs that are reserved specifically for private use only. This IP address cannot be used for devices on the Internet as they are non-routable. Private Address: IPv4 Class Private IPv4 Start Address Private IPv4 End Address\nA 10.0.0.0 10.255.255.255\nB 172.16.0.0 172.31.255.255\nC 192.168.0.0 192.168.255.255 IPv4 Class Private IPv4 Start Address Private IPv4 End Address\nA 10.0.0.0 10.255.255.255\nB 172.16.0.0 172.31.255.255\nC 192.168.0.0 192.168.255.255 IPv4 Class Private IPv4 Start Address Private IPv4 End Address IPv4 Class Private IPv4 Start Address Private IPv4 End Address IPv4 Class Private IPv4 Start Address Private IPv4 End Address A 10.0.0.0 10.255.255.255\nB 172.16.0.0 172.31.255.255\nC 192.168.0.0 192.168.255.255 A 10.0.0.0 10.255.255.255 A 10.0.0.0 10.255.255.255 B 172.16.0.0 172.31.255.255 B 172.16.0.0 172.31.255.255 C 192.168.0.0 192.168.255.255 C 192.168.0.0 192.168.255.255 Special Address: IP Range from 127.0.0.1 to 127.255.255.255 are network testing addresses also known as loopback addresses are the special IP address. Special Address:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is the DNS?",
        "answer": "DNS is the Domain Name System. It is considered as the devices/services directory of the Internet. It is a decentralized and hierarchical naming system for devices/services connected to the Internet. It translates the domain names to their corresponding IPs. For e.g. interviewbit.com to 172.217.166.36. It uses port 53 by default.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is the use of a router and how is it different from a gateway?",
        "answer": "The router is a networking device used for connecting two or more network segments. It directs the traffic in the network. It transfers information and data like web pages, emails, images, videos, etc. from source to destination in the form of packets. It operates at the network layer. The gateways are also used to route and regulate the network traffic but, they can also send data between two dissimilar networks while a router can only send data to similar networks.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is the SMTP protocol?",
        "answer": "SMTP is the Simple Mail Transfer Protocol. SMTP sets the rule for communication between servers. This set of rules helps the software to transmit emails over the internet. It supports both End-to-End and Store-and-Forward methods. It is in always-listening mode on port 25. SMTP Protocol  SMTP Protocol",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Describe the OSI Reference Model",
        "answer": "Open System Interconnections (OSI) is a network architecture model based on the ISO standards. It is called the OSI model as it deals with connecting the systems that are open for communication with other systems. The OSI model has seven layers. The principles used to arrive at the seven layers can be summarized  briefly as below: Create a new layer if a different abstraction is needed.\nEach layer should have a well-defined function.\nThe function of each layer is chosen based on internationally standardized protocols. Create a new layer if a different abstraction is needed. Each layer should have a well-defined function. The function of each layer is chosen based on internationally standardized protocols.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Define the 7 different layers of the OSI Reference Model",
        "answer": "Here the 7 layers of the OSI reference model: Layers of OSI Model  Layers of OSI Model Layer Unit Exchanged Description\nPhysical Bit\nIt is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel.\nChooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex.,\nData Link Frame\nThe main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors.\nIt also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code.\nWhen more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time.\nIt is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing.\nNetwork Packet\nIt controls the operation of the subnet.\nThe network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages.\nTransport TPDU - Transaction Protocol Data Unit\nThe basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end.\nThe Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly.\nSession SPDU - Session Protocol Data Unit\nThe session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them.\nDialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal.\nPresentation PPDU - Presentation Protocol Data Unit\nThe presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted.\nIt translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver.\nApplication APDU - Application Protocol Data Unit\nIt contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users.\nThe application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer. Layer Unit Exchanged Description\nPhysical Bit\nIt is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel.\nChooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex.,\nData Link Frame\nThe main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors.\nIt also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code.\nWhen more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time.\nIt is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing.\nNetwork Packet\nIt controls the operation of the subnet.\nThe network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages.\nTransport TPDU - Transaction Protocol Data Unit\nThe basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end.\nThe Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly.\nSession SPDU - Session Protocol Data Unit\nThe session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them.\nDialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal.\nPresentation PPDU - Presentation Protocol Data Unit\nThe presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted.\nIt translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver.\nApplication APDU - Application Protocol Data Unit\nIt contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users.\nThe application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer. Layer Unit Exchanged Description Layer Unit Exchanged Description Layer Unit Exchanged Description Physical Bit\nIt is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel.\nChooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex.,\nData Link Frame\nThe main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors.\nIt also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code.\nWhen more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time.\nIt is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing.\nNetwork Packet\nIt controls the operation of the subnet.\nThe network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages.\nTransport TPDU - Transaction Protocol Data Unit\nThe basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end.\nThe Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly.\nSession SPDU - Session Protocol Data Unit\nThe session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them.\nDialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal.\nPresentation PPDU - Presentation Protocol Data Unit\nThe presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted.\nIt translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver.\nApplication APDU - Application Protocol Data Unit\nIt contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users.\nThe application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer. Physical Bit\nIt is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel.\nChooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex., Physical Bit It is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel.\nChooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex., It is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel.\nChooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex., It is concerned with transmitting raw bits over a communication channel. Chooses which type of transmission mode is to be selected for the transmission. The available transmission modes are Simplex, Half Duplex and Full Duplex., Data Link Frame\nThe main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors.\nIt also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code.\nWhen more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time.\nIt is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing. Data Link Frame The main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors.\nIt also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code.\nWhen more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time.\nIt is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing. The main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors.\nIt also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code.\nWhen more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time.\nIt is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing. The main task of this layer is to transform a raw transmission facility into a line that appears free of undetected transmission errors. It also allows detecting damaged packets using the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) error-detecting, code. When more than one node is connected to a shared link, Data Link Layer protocols are required to determine which device has control over the link at a given time. It is implemented by protocols like CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, ALOHA, and Token Passing. Network Packet\nIt controls the operation of the subnet.\nThe network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages. Network Packet It controls the operation of the subnet.\nThe network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages. It controls the operation of the subnet.\nThe network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages. It controls the operation of the subnet. The network layer takes care of feedback messaging through ICMP messages. Transport TPDU - Transaction Protocol Data Unit\nThe basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end.\nThe Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly. Transport TPDU - Transaction Protocol Data Unit The basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end.\nThe Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly. The basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end.\nThe Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly. The basic functionality of this layer is to accept data from the above layers, split it up into smaller units if needed, pass these to the network layer, and ensure that all the pieces arrive correctly at the other end. The Transport Layer takes care of Segmentation and Reassembly. Session SPDU - Session Protocol Data Unit\nThe session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them.\nDialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal. Session SPDU - Session Protocol Data Unit The session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them.\nDialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal. The session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them.\nDialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal. The session layer allows users on different machines to establish sessions between them. Dialogue control is using the full-duplex link as half-duplex. It sends out dummy packets from the client to the server when the client is ideal. Presentation PPDU - Presentation Protocol Data Unit\nThe presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted.\nIt translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver. Presentation PPDU - Presentation Protocol Data Unit The presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted.\nIt translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver. The presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted.\nIt translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver. The presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information transmitted. It translates a message from a common form to the encoded format which will be understood by the receiver. Application APDU - Application Protocol Data Unit\nIt contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users.\nThe application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer. Application APDU - Application Protocol Data Unit It contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users.\nThe application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer. It contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users.\nThe application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer. It contains a variety of protocols that are commonly needed by users. The application layer sends data of any size to the transport layer.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Describe the TCP/IP Reference Model",
        "answer": "It is a compressed version of the OSI model with only 4 layers. It was developed by the US Department of Defence (DoD) in the 1980s. The name of this model is based on 2 standard protocols used i.e. TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) and IP (Internet Protocol).",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Define the 4 different layers of the TCP/IP Reference Model",
        "answer": "Layers of TCP/IP  Layers of TCP/IP Layer Description\nLink Decides which links such as serial lines or classic Ethernet must be used to meet the needs of the connectionless internet layer.\nInternet\nThe internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together.\nIt delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered.\nTransport Its functionality is almost the same as the OSI transport layer. It enables peer entities on the network to carry on a conversation.\nApplication It contains all the higher-level protocols. Layer Description\nLink Decides which links such as serial lines or classic Ethernet must be used to meet the needs of the connectionless internet layer.\nInternet\nThe internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together.\nIt delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered.\nTransport Its functionality is almost the same as the OSI transport layer. It enables peer entities on the network to carry on a conversation.\nApplication It contains all the higher-level protocols. Layer Description Layer Description Layer Description Link Decides which links such as serial lines or classic Ethernet must be used to meet the needs of the connectionless internet layer.\nInternet\nThe internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together.\nIt delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered.\nTransport Its functionality is almost the same as the OSI transport layer. It enables peer entities on the network to carry on a conversation.\nApplication It contains all the higher-level protocols. Link Decides which links such as serial lines or classic Ethernet must be used to meet the needs of the connectionless internet layer. Link Decides which links such as serial lines or classic Ethernet must be used to meet the needs of the connectionless internet layer. Internet\nThe internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together.\nIt delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered. Internet The internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together.\nIt delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered. The internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together.\nIt delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered. The internet layer is the most important layer which holds the whole architecture together. It delivers the IP packets where they are supposed to be delivered. Transport Its functionality is almost the same as the OSI transport layer. It enables peer entities on the network to carry on a conversation. Transport Its functionality is almost the same as the OSI transport layer. It enables peer entities on the network to carry on a conversation. Application It contains all the higher-level protocols. Application It contains all the higher-level protocols.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Differentiate OSI Reference Model with TCP/IP Reference Model",
        "answer": "OSI Vs TCP/IP  OSI Vs TCP/IP OSI Reference Model TCP/IP Reference Model\n7 layered architecture 4 layered architecture\nFixed boundaries and functionality for each layer Flexible architecture with no strict boundaries between layers\nLow Reliability High Reliability\nVertical Layer Approach Horizontal Layer Approach OSI Reference Model TCP/IP Reference Model\n7 layered architecture 4 layered architecture\nFixed boundaries and functionality for each layer Flexible architecture with no strict boundaries between layers\nLow Reliability High Reliability\nVertical Layer Approach Horizontal Layer Approach OSI Reference Model TCP/IP Reference Model OSI Reference Model TCP/IP Reference Model OSI Reference Model TCP/IP Reference Model 7 layered architecture 4 layered architecture\nFixed boundaries and functionality for each layer Flexible architecture with no strict boundaries between layers\nLow Reliability High Reliability\nVertical Layer Approach Horizontal Layer Approach 7 layered architecture 4 layered architecture 7 layered architecture 4 layered architecture Fixed boundaries and functionality for each layer Flexible architecture with no strict boundaries between layers Fixed boundaries and functionality for each layer Flexible architecture with no strict boundaries between layers Low Reliability High Reliability Low Reliability High Reliability Vertical Layer Approach Horizontal Layer Approach Vertical Layer Approach Horizontal Layer Approach",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What are the HTTP and the HTTPS protocol?",
        "answer": "HTTP is the HyperText Transfer Protocol which defines the set of rules and standards on how the information can be transmitted on the World Wide Web (WWW).  It helps the web browsers and web servers for communication. It is a ‘stateless protocol’ where each command is independent with respect to the previous command. HTTP is an application layer protocol built upon the TCP. It uses port 80 by default. HTTPS is the HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure or Secure HTTP. It is an advanced and secured version of HTTP. On top of HTTP, SSL/TLS protocol is used to provide security. It enables secure transactions by encrypting the communication and also helps identify network servers securely. It uses port 443 by default.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is the FTP protocol?",
        "answer": "FTP is a File Transfer Protocol. It is an application layer protocol used to transfer files and data reliably and efficiently between hosts. It can also be used to download files from remote servers to your computer. It uses port 27 by default.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is the TCP protocol?",
        "answer": "TCP or TCP/IP is the Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol. It is a set of rules that decides how a computer connects to the Internet and how to transmit the data over the network. It creates a virtual network when more than one computer is connected to the network and uses the three ways handshake model to establish the connection which makes it more reliable.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is the UDP protocol?",
        "answer": "UDP is the User Datagram Protocol and is based on Datagrams. Mainly, it is used for multicasting and broadcasting. Its functionality is almost the same as TCP/IP Protocol except for the three ways of handshaking and error checking. It uses a simple transmission without any hand-shaking which makes it less reliable.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Compare between TCP and UDP",
        "answer": "TCP/IP UDP\nConnection-Oriented Protocol Connectionless Protocol\nMore Reliable Less Reliable\nSlower Transmission Faster Transmission\nPackets order can be preserved or can be rearranged Packets order is not fixed and packets are independent of each other\nUses three ways handshake model for connection No handshake for establishing the connection\nTCP packets are heavy-weight UDP packets are light-weight\nOffers error checking mechanism No error checking mechanism\nProtocols like HTTP, FTP, Telnet, SMTP, HTTPS, etc use TCP at the transport layer Protocols like DNS, RIP, SNMP, RTP, BOOTP, TFTP, NIP, etc use UDP at the transport layer TCP/IP UDP\nConnection-Oriented Protocol Connectionless Protocol\nMore Reliable Less Reliable\nSlower Transmission Faster Transmission\nPackets order can be preserved or can be rearranged Packets order is not fixed and packets are independent of each other\nUses three ways handshake model for connection No handshake for establishing the connection\nTCP packets are heavy-weight UDP packets are light-weight\nOffers error checking mechanism No error checking mechanism\nProtocols like HTTP, FTP, Telnet, SMTP, HTTPS, etc use TCP at the transport layer Protocols like DNS, RIP, SNMP, RTP, BOOTP, TFTP, NIP, etc use UDP at the transport layer TCP/IP UDP TCP/IP UDP TCP/IP UDP Connection-Oriented Protocol Connectionless Protocol\nMore Reliable Less Reliable\nSlower Transmission Faster Transmission\nPackets order can be preserved or can be rearranged Packets order is not fixed and packets are independent of each other\nUses three ways handshake model for connection No handshake for establishing the connection\nTCP packets are heavy-weight UDP packets are light-weight\nOffers error checking mechanism No error checking mechanism\nProtocols like HTTP, FTP, Telnet, SMTP, HTTPS, etc use TCP at the transport layer Protocols like DNS, RIP, SNMP, RTP, BOOTP, TFTP, NIP, etc use UDP at the transport layer Connection-Oriented Protocol Connectionless Protocol Connection-Oriented Protocol Connectionless Protocol More Reliable Less Reliable More Reliable Less Reliable Slower Transmission Faster Transmission Slower Transmission Faster Transmission Packets order can be preserved or can be rearranged Packets order is not fixed and packets are independent of each other Packets order can be preserved or can be rearranged Packets order is not fixed and packets are independent of each other Uses three ways handshake model for connection No handshake for establishing the connection Uses three ways handshake model for connection No handshake for establishing the connection TCP packets are heavy-weight UDP packets are light-weight TCP packets are heavy-weight UDP packets are light-weight Offers error checking mechanism No error checking mechanism Offers error checking mechanism No error checking mechanism Protocols like HTTP, FTP, Telnet, SMTP, HTTPS, etc use TCP at the transport layer Protocols like DNS, RIP, SNMP, RTP, BOOTP, TFTP, NIP, etc use UDP at the transport layer Protocols like HTTP, FTP, Telnet, SMTP, HTTPS, etc use TCP at the transport layer Protocols like DNS, RIP, SNMP, RTP, BOOTP, TFTP, NIP, etc use UDP at the transport layer TCP VS UDP  TCP VS UDP",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is the ICMP protocol?",
        "answer": "ICMP is the Internet Control Message Protocol. It is a network layer protocol used for error handling. It is mainly used by network devices like routers for diagnosing the network connection issues and crucial for error reporting and testing if the data is reaching the preferred destination in time. It uses port 7 by default.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What do you mean by the DHCP Protocol?",
        "answer": "DHCP is the Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol. It is an application layer protocol used to auto-configure devices on IP networks enabling them to use the TCP and UDP-based protocols. The DHCP servers auto-assign the IPs and other network configurations to the devices individually which enables them to communicate over the IP network. It helps to get the subnet mask, IP address and helps to resolve the DNS. It uses port 67 by default.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is the ARP protocol?",
        "answer": "ARP is Address Resolution Protocol. It is a network-level protocol used to convert the logical address i.e. IP address to the device's physical address i.e. MAC address. It can also be used to get the MAC address of devices when they are trying to communicate over the local network. ARP Protocol  ARP Protocol",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is the MAC address and how is it related to NIC?",
        "answer": "MAC address is the Media Access Control address. It is a 48-bit or 64-bit unique identifier of devices in the network. It is also called the physical address embedded with Network Interface Card (NIC) used at the Data Link Layer. NIC is a hardware component in the networking device using which a device can connect to the network.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Differentiate the MAC address with the IP address",
        "answer": "The difference between MAC address and IP address are as follows: MAC Address IP Address\nMedia Access Control Address Internet Protocol Address\n6 or 8-byte hexadecimal number 4 (IPv4) or 16 (IPv6) Byte address\nIt is embedded with NIC It is obtained from the network\nPhysical Address Logical Address\nOperates at Data Link Layer Operates at Network Layer.\nHelps to identify the device Helps to identify the device connectivity on the network. MAC Address IP Address\nMedia Access Control Address Internet Protocol Address\n6 or 8-byte hexadecimal number 4 (IPv4) or 16 (IPv6) Byte address\nIt is embedded with NIC It is obtained from the network\nPhysical Address Logical Address\nOperates at Data Link Layer Operates at Network Layer.\nHelps to identify the device Helps to identify the device connectivity on the network. MAC Address IP Address MAC Address IP Address MAC Address IP Address Media Access Control Address Internet Protocol Address\n6 or 8-byte hexadecimal number 4 (IPv4) or 16 (IPv6) Byte address\nIt is embedded with NIC It is obtained from the network\nPhysical Address Logical Address\nOperates at Data Link Layer Operates at Network Layer.\nHelps to identify the device Helps to identify the device connectivity on the network. Media Access Control Address Internet Protocol Address Media Access Control Address Internet Protocol Address 6 or 8-byte hexadecimal number 4 (IPv4) or 16 (IPv6) Byte address 6 or 8-byte hexadecimal number 4 (IPv4) or 16 (IPv6) Byte address It is embedded with NIC It is obtained from the network It is embedded with NIC It is obtained from the network Physical Address Logical Address Physical Address Logical Address Operates at Data Link Layer Operates at Network Layer. Operates at Data Link Layer Operates at Network Layer. Helps to identify the device Helps to identify the device connectivity on the network. Helps to identify the device Helps to identify the device connectivity on the network.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is a subnet?",
        "answer": "A subnet is a network inside a network achieved by the process called subnetting which helps divide a network into subnets. It is used for getting a higher routing efficiency and enhances the security of the network. It reduces the time to extract the host address from the routing table. Subnet  Subnet",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Compare the hub vs switch",
        "answer": "Hub Switch\nOperates at Physical Layer Operates at Data Link Layer\nHalf-Duplex transmission mode Full-Duplex transmission mode\nEthernet devices can be connectedsend LAN devices can be connected\nLess complex, less intelligent, and cheaper Intelligent and effective\nNo software support for the administration Administration software support is present\nLess speed up to 100 MBPS Supports high speed in GBPS\nLess efficient as there is no way to avoid collisions when more than one nodes sends the packets at the same time More efficient as the collisions can be avoided or reduced as compared to Hub Hub Switch\nOperates at Physical Layer Operates at Data Link Layer\nHalf-Duplex transmission mode Full-Duplex transmission mode\nEthernet devices can be connectedsend LAN devices can be connected\nLess complex, less intelligent, and cheaper Intelligent and effective\nNo software support for the administration Administration software support is present\nLess speed up to 100 MBPS Supports high speed in GBPS\nLess efficient as there is no way to avoid collisions when more than one nodes sends the packets at the same time More efficient as the collisions can be avoided or reduced as compared to Hub Hub Switch Hub Switch Hub Switch Operates at Physical Layer Operates at Data Link Layer\nHalf-Duplex transmission mode Full-Duplex transmission mode\nEthernet devices can be connectedsend LAN devices can be connected\nLess complex, less intelligent, and cheaper Intelligent and effective\nNo software support for the administration Administration software support is present\nLess speed up to 100 MBPS Supports high speed in GBPS\nLess efficient as there is no way to avoid collisions when more than one nodes sends the packets at the same time More efficient as the collisions can be avoided or reduced as compared to Hub Operates at Physical Layer Operates at Data Link Layer Operates at Physical Layer Operates at Data Link Layer Half-Duplex transmission mode Full-Duplex transmission mode Half-Duplex transmission mode Full-Duplex transmission mode Ethernet devices can be connectedsend LAN devices can be connected Ethernet devices can be connectedsend LAN devices can be connected Less complex, less intelligent, and cheaper Intelligent and effective Less complex, less intelligent, and cheaper Intelligent and effective No software support for the administration Administration software support is present No software support for the administration Administration software support is present Less speed up to 100 MBPS Supports high speed in GBPS Less speed up to 100 MBPS Supports high speed in GBPS Less efficient as there is no way to avoid collisions when more than one nodes sends the packets at the same time More efficient as the collisions can be avoided or reduced as compared to Hub Less efficient as there is no way to avoid collisions when more than one nodes sends the packets at the same time More efficient as the collisions can be avoided or reduced as compared to Hub",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is the difference between the ipconfig and the ifconfig?",
        "answer": "ipconfig ifconfig\nInternet Protocol Configuration Interface Configuration\nCommand used in Microsoft operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Command used in MAC, Linux, UNIX operating systems to view and configure network interfaces\nUsed to get the TCP/IP summary and allows to changes the DHCP and DNS settings ipconfig ifconfig\nInternet Protocol Configuration Interface Configuration\nCommand used in Microsoft operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Command used in MAC, Linux, UNIX operating systems to view and configure network interfaces\nUsed to get the TCP/IP summary and allows to changes the DHCP and DNS settings ipconfig ifconfig ipconfig ifconfig ipconfig ifconfig Internet Protocol Configuration Interface Configuration\nCommand used in Microsoft operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Command used in MAC, Linux, UNIX operating systems to view and configure network interfaces\nUsed to get the TCP/IP summary and allows to changes the DHCP and DNS settings Internet Protocol Configuration Interface Configuration Internet Protocol Configuration Interface Configuration Command used in Microsoft operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Command used in MAC, Linux, UNIX operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Command used in Microsoft operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Command used in MAC, Linux, UNIX operating systems to view and configure network interfaces Used to get the TCP/IP summary and allows to changes the DHCP and DNS settings Used to get the TCP/IP summary and allows to changes the DHCP and DNS settings Used to get the TCP/IP summary and allows to changes the DHCP and DNS settings",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What is the firewall?",
        "answer": "The firewall is a network security system that is used to monitor the incoming and outgoing traffic and blocks the same based on the firewall security policies. It acts as a wall between the internet (public network) and the networking devices (a private network). It is either a hardware device, software program, or a combination of both. It adds a layer of security to the network. Firewall  Firewall",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What are Unicasting, Anycasting, Multicasting and Broadcasting?",
        "answer": "Unicasting: If the message is sent to a single node from the source then it is known as unicasting. This is commonly used in networks to establish a new connection.\nAnycasting: If the message is sent to any of the nodes from the source then it is known as anycasting. It is mainly used to get the content from any of the servers in the Content Delivery System.\nMulticasting: If the message is sent to a subset of nodes from the source then it is known as multicasting. Used to send the same data to multiple receivers. \nBroadcasting: If the message is sent to all the nodes in a network from a source then it is known as broadcasting. DHCP and ARP in the local network use broadcasting. Unicasting: If the message is sent to a single node from the source then it is known as unicasting. This is commonly used in networks to establish a new connection. Unicasting: Anycasting: If the message is sent to any of the nodes from the source then it is known as anycasting. It is mainly used to get the content from any of the servers in the Content Delivery System. Anycasting: Multicasting: If the message is sent to a subset of nodes from the source then it is known as multicasting. Used to send the same data to multiple receivers. Multicasting: Broadcasting: If the message is sent to all the nodes in a network from a source then it is known as broadcasting. DHCP and ARP in the local network use broadcasting. Broadcasting:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What happens when you enter google.com in the web browser?",
        "answer": "Below are the steps that are being followed: Check the browser cache first if the content is fresh and present in cache display the same.\nIf not, the browser checks if the IP of the URL is present in the cache (browser and OS) if not then request the OS to do a DNS lookup using UDP to get the corresponding IP address of the URL from the DNS server to establish a new TCP connection.\nA new TCP connection is set between the browser and the server using three-way handshaking.\nAn HTTP request is sent to the server using the TCP connection.\nThe web servers running on the Servers handle the incoming HTTP request and send the HTTP response.\nThe browser process the HTTP response sent by the server and may close the TCP connection or reuse the same for future requests.\nIf the response data is cacheable then browsers cache the same.\nBrowser decodes the response and renders the content. Check the browser cache first if the content is fresh and present in cache display the same. If not, the browser checks if the IP of the URL is present in the cache (browser and OS) if not then request the OS to do a DNS lookup using UDP to get the corresponding IP address of the URL from the DNS server to establish a new TCP connection. A new TCP connection is set between the browser and the server using three-way handshaking. An HTTP request is sent to the server using the TCP connection. The web servers running on the Servers handle the incoming HTTP request and send the HTTP response. The browser process the HTTP response sent by the server and may close the TCP connection or reuse the same for future requests. If the response data is cacheable then browsers cache the same. Browser decodes the response and renders the content. Conclusion In today’s world, it is very hard to stay away from the Internet and that is what makes networking one of the most important interview topics. As of 2021 if we check the facts, there is a total of 1.3 million kilometers of submarine optical fiber cables set globally to connect the world to the Internet. These cables are more than enough to revolve around the earth more than 100 times. Resources Learn Coding Learn Coding How To Become Network Engineer How To Become Network Engineer Network Engineer Salary Network Engineer Salary Difference Between Hub and Switch Difference Between Hub and Switch",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is the network?",
        "answer": "ADVERTISEMENT\nA network is a set of devices that are connected with a physical media link. In a network, two or more nodes are connected by a physical link or two or more networks are connected by one or more nodes.\nA network is a collection of devices connected to each other to allow the sharing of data.\nExample of a network is an internet. An internet connects the millions of people across the world.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What do you mean by network topology?",
        "answer": "Network topology specifies the layout of a computer network. It shows how devices and cables are connected to each other. The types of topologies are:\nBus:\n\nBus topology is a network topology in which all the nodes are connected to a single cable known as a central cable or bus.\nIt acts as a shared communication medium, i.e., if any device wants to send the data to other devices, then it will send the data over the bus which in turn sends the data to all the attached devices.\nBus topology is useful for a small number of devices. As if the bus is damaged then the whole network fails.\nStar:\nADVERTISEMENT\n\nStar topology is a network topology in which all the nodes are connected to a single device known as a central device.\nStar topology requires more cable compared to other topologies. Therefore, it is more robust as a failure in one cable will only disconnect a specific computer connected to this cable.\nIf the central device is damaged, then the whole network fails.\nStar topology is very easy to install, manage and troubleshoot.\nStar topology is commonly used in office and home networks.\nRing\n\n\nRing topology is a network topology in which nodes are exactly connected to two or more nodes and thus, forming a single continuous path for the transmission.\nIt does not need any central server to control the connectivity among the nodes.\nIf the single node is damaged, then the whole network fails.\nRing topology is very rarely used as it is expensive, difficult to install and manage.\nExamples of Ring topology are SONET network, SDH network, etc.\nMesh\n\n\n\nMesh topology is a network topology in which all the nodes are individually connected to other nodes.\nIt does not need any central switch or hub to control the connectivity among the nodes.\nMesh topology is categorized into two parts:\nFully connected mesh topology: In this topology, all the nodes are connected to each other.\nPartially connected mesh topology: In this topology, all the nodes are not connected to each other.\nIt is a robust as a failure in one cable will only disconnect the specified computer connected to this cable.\nMesh topology is rarely used as installation and configuration are difficult when connectivity gets more.\nCabling cost is high as it requires bulk wiring.\nTree\n\n\nTree topology is a combination of star and bus topology. It is also known as the expanded star topology.\nIn tree topology, all the star networks are connected to a single bus.\nEthernet protocol is used in this topology.\nIn this, the whole network is divided into segments known as star networks which can be easily maintained. If one segment is damaged, but there is no effect on other segments.\nTree topology depends on the \"main bus,\" and if it breaks, then the whole network gets damaged.\nHybrid\nA hybrid topology is a combination of different topologies to form a resulting topology.\nIf star topology is connected with another star topology, then it remains star topology. If star topology is connected with different topology, then it becomes a Hybrid topology.\nIt provides flexibility as it can be implemented in a different network environment.\nThe weakness of a topology is ignored, and only strength will be taken into consideration.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What are the advantages of Distributed Processing?",
        "answer": "A list of advantages of distributed processing:\nSecure\nSupport Encapsulation\nDistributed database\nFaster Problem solving\nSecurity through redundancy\nCollaborative Processing",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What is the criteria to check the network reliability?",
        "answer": "Network reliability: Network reliability means the ability of the network to carry out the desired operation through a network such as communication through a network.\nNetwork reliability plays a significant role in the network functionality. The network monitoring systems and devices are the essential requirements for making the network reliable.The network monitoring system identifies the problems that are occurred in the network while the network devices ensure that data should reach the appropriate destination.\n\nThe reliability of a network can be measured by the following factors:\nDowntime: The downtime is defined as the required time to recover.\nFailure Frequency: It is the frequency when it fails to work the way it is intended.\nCatastrophe: It indicates that the network has been attacked by some unexpected event such as fire, earthquake.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) Which are the different factors that affect the security of a network?",
        "answer": "There are mainly two security affecting factors:\nUnauthorized Access\nViruses",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) Which are the different factors that affect the reliability of a network?",
        "answer": "The following factors affect the reliability of a network:\nFrequency of failure\nRecovery time of a network after a failure",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) Which are the different factors that affect the performance of a network?",
        "answer": "The following factors affect the performance of a network:\nLarge number of users\nTransmission medium types\nHardware\nSoftware",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What makes a network effective and efficient?",
        "answer": "There are mainly two criteria which make a network effective and efficient:\nPerformance: : performance can be measured in many ways like transmit time and response time.\nReliability: reliability is measured by frequency of failure.\nRobustness: robustness specifies the quality or condition of being strong and in good condition.\nSecurity: It specifies how to protect data from unauthorized access and viruses.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What is bandwidth?",
        "answer": "Every signal has a limit of upper range frequency and lower range frequency. The range of limit of network between its upper and lower frequency is called bandwidth.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What is a node and link?",
        "answer": "A network is a connection setup of two or more computers directly connected by some physical mediums like optical fiber or coaxial cable. This physical medium of connection is known as a link, and the computers that it is connected are known as nodes.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What is a gateway? Is there any difference between a gateway and router?",
        "answer": "A node that is connected to two or more networks is commonly known as a gateway. It is also known as a router. It is used to forward messages from one network to another. Both the gateway and router regulate the traffic in the network.\nDifferences between gateway and router:\nA router sends the data between two similar networks while gateway sends the data between two dissimilar networks.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What is DNS?",
        "answer": "DNS is an acronym stands for Domain Name System.\nDNS was introduced by Paul Mockapetris and Jon Postel in 1983.\nIt is a naming system for all the resources over the internet which includes physical nodes and applications. It is used to locate to resource easily over a network.\nDNS is an internet which maps the domain names to their associated IP addresses.\nWithout DNS, users must know the IP address of the web page that you wanted to access.\n\nWorking of DNS:\nIf you want to visit the website of \"javaTpoint\", then the user will type \"https://www.javatpoint.com\" into the address bar of the web browser. Once the domain name is entered, then the domain name system will translate the domain name into the IP address which can be easily interpreted by the computer. Using the IP address, the computer can locate the web page requested by the user.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What is DNS forwarder?",
        "answer": "A forwarder is used with DNS server when it receives DNS queries that cannot be resolved quickly. So it forwards those requests to external DNS servers for resolution.\nA DNS server which is configured as a forwarder will behave differently than the DNS server which is not configured as a forwarder.\nFollowing are the ways that the DNS server behaves when it is configured as a forwarder:\nWhen the DNS server receives the query, then it resolves the query by using a cache.\nIf the DNS server is not able to resolve the query, then it forwards the query to another DNS server.\nIf the forwarder is not available, then it will try to resolve the query by using root hint.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What is NIC?",
        "answer": "NIC stands for Network Interface Card. It is a peripheral card attached to the PC to connect to a network. Every NIC has its own MAC address that identifies the PC on the network.\nIt provides a wireless connection to a local area network.\nNICs were mainly used in desktop computers.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What is the meaning of 10Base-T?",
        "answer": "It is used to specify data transfer rate. In 10Base-T, 10 specify the data transfer rate, i.e., 10Mbps. The word Base specifies the baseband as opposed to broadband. T specifies the type of the cable which is a twisted pair.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What is NOS in computer networking?",
        "answer": "NOS stands for Network Operating System. It is specialized software which is used to provide network connectivity to a computer to make communication possible with other computers and connected devices.\nNOS is the software which allows the device to communicate, share files with other devices.\nThe first network operating system was Novel NetWare released in 1983. Some other examples of NOS are Windows 2000, Windows XP, Linux, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What are the different types of networks?",
        "answer": "Networks can be divided on the basis of area of distribution. For example:\nPAN (Personal Area Network): Its range limit is up to 10 meters. It is created for personal use. Generally, personal devices are connected to this network. For example computers, telephones, fax, printers, etc.\nLAN (Local Area Network): It is used for a small geographical location like office, hospital, school, etc.\nHAN (House Area Network): It is actually a LAN that is used within a house and used to connect homely devices like personal computers, phones, printers, etc.\nCAN (Campus Area Network): It is a connection of devices within a campus area which links to other departments of the organization within the same campus.\nMAN (Metropolitan Area Network): It is used to connect the devices which span to large cities like metropolitan cities over a wide geographical area.\nWAN (Wide Area Network): It is used over a wide geographical location that may range to connect cities and countries.\nGAN (Global Area Network): It uses satellites to connect devices over global are.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What is POP3?",
        "answer": "POP3 stands for Post Office Protocol version3. POP is responsible for accessing the mail service on a client machine. POP3 works on two models such as Delete mode and Keep mode.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What do you understand by MAC address?",
        "answer": "MAC stands for Media Access Control. It is the address of the device at the Media Access Control Layer of Network Architecture. It is a unique address means no two devices can have same MAC addresses.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What is IP address?",
        "answer": "IP address is a unique 32 bit software address of a computer in a network system.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What is private IP address?",
        "answer": "There are three ranges of IP addresses that have been reserved for IP addresses. They are not valid for use on the internet. If you want to access internet on these private IPs, you must have to use proxy server or NAT server.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What is public IP address?",
        "answer": "A public IP address is an address taken by the Internet Service Provider which facilitates you to communication on the internet.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) What is APIPA?",
        "answer": "APIPA is an acronym stands for Automatic Private IP Addressing. This feature is generally found in Microsoft operating system.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What is the full form of ADS?",
        "answer": "ADS stands for Active Directory Structure.\nADS is a microsoft technology used to manage the computers and other devices.\nADS allows the network administrators to manage the domains, users and objects within the network.\nADS consists of three main tiers:\nDomain: Users that use the same database will be grouped into a single domain.\nTree: Multiple domains can be grouped into a single tree.\nForest: Multiple trees can be grouped into a single forest.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What is RAID?",
        "answer": "RAID is a method to provide Fault Tolerance by using multiple Hard Disc Drives.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) What is anonymous FTP?",
        "answer": "Anonymous FTP is used to grant users access to files in public servers. Users which are allowed access to data in these servers do not need to identify themselves, but instead log in as an anonymous guest.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What is protocol?",
        "answer": "A protocol is a set of rules which is used to govern all the aspects of information communication.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) What are the main elements of a protocol?",
        "answer": "The main elements of a protocol are:\nSyntax: It specifies the structure or format of the data. It also specifies the order in which they are presented.\nSemantics: It specifies the meaning of each section of bits.\nTiming: Timing specifies two characteristics: When data should be sent and how fast it can be sent.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "29 What is the Domain Name System?",
        "answer": "There are two types of client/server programs. First is directly used by the users and the second supports application programs.\nThe Domain Name System is the second type supporting program that is used by other programs such as to find the IP address of an e-mail recipient.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is link?",
        "answer": "A link is connectivity between two devices which includes the cables and protocols used in order to make communication between devices.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) How many layers are in OSI reference model?",
        "answer": "OSI reference model: OSI reference model is an ISO standard which defines a networking framework for implementing the protocols in seven layers. These seven layers can be grouped into three categories:\nNetwork layer: Layer 1, Layer 2 and layer 3 are the network layers.\nTransport layer: Layer 4 is a transport layer.\nApplication layer. Layer 5, Layer 6 and Layer 7 are the application layers.\nThere are 7 layers in the OSI reference model.\n1. Physical Layer\nIt is the lowest layer of the OSI reference model.\nIt is used for the transmission of an unstructured raw bit stream over a physical medium.\nPhysical layer transmits the data either in the form of electrical/optical or mechanical form.\nThe physical layer is mainly used for the physical connection between the devices, and such physical connection can be made by using twisted-pair cable, fibre-optic or wireless transmission media.\n2. DataLink Layer\nIt is used for transferring the data from one node to another node.\nIt receives the data from the network layer and converts the data into data frames and then attach the physical address to these frames which are sent to the physical layer.\nIt enables the error-free transfer of data from one node to another node.\nFunctions of Data-link layer:\n\nFrame synchronization: Data-link layer converts the data into frames, and it ensures that the destination must recognize the starting and ending of each frame.\nFlow control: Data-link layer controls the data flow within the network.\nError control: It detects and corrects the error occurred during the transmission from source to destination.\nAddressing: Data-link layer attach the physical address with the data frames so that the individual machines can be easily identified.\nLink management: Data-link layer manages the initiation, maintenance and, termination of the link between the source and destination for the effective exchange of data.\n3. Network Layer\nNetwork layer converts the logical address into the physical address.\nIt provides the routing concept means it determines the best route for the packet to travel from source to the destination.\nFunctions of network layer:\n\nRouting: The network layer determines the best route from source to destination. This function is known as routing.\nLogical addressing: The network layer defines the addressing scheme to identify each device uniquely.\nPacketizing: The network layer receives the data from the upper layer and converts the data into packets. This process is known as packetizing.\nInternetworking: The network layer provides the logical connection between the different types of networks for forming a bigger network.\nFragmentation: It is a process of dividing the packets into the fragments.\n4. Transport Layer\nIt delivers the message through the network and provides error checking so that no error occurs during the transfer of data.\nIt provides two kinds of services:\nConnection-oriented transmission: In this transmission, the receiver sends the acknowledgement to the sender after the packet has been received.\nConnectionless transmission: In this transmission, the receiver does not send the acknowledgement to the sender.\n5. Session Layer\nThe main responsibility of the session layer is beginning, maintaining and ending the communication between the devices.\nSession layer also reports the error coming from the upper layers.\nSession layer establishes and maintains the session between the two users.\n6. Presentation Layer\nThe presentation layer is also known as a Translation layer as it translates the data from one format to another format.\nAt the sender side, this layer translates the data format used by the application layer to the common format and at the receiver side, this layer translates the common format into a format used by the application layer.\nFunctions of presentation layer:\nCharacter code translation\nData conversion\nData compression\nData encryption\n7. Application Layer\nApplication layer enables the user to access the network.\nIt is the topmost layer of the OSI reference model.\nApplication layer protocols are file transfer protocol, simple mail transfer protocol, domain name system, etc.\nThe most widely used application protocol is HTTP(Hypertext transfer protocol ). A user sends the request for the web page using HTTP.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What is the usage of OSI physical layer?",
        "answer": "The OSI physical layer is used to convert data bits into electrical signals and vice versa. On this layer, network devices and cable types are considered and setup.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) Explain the functionality of OSI session layer?",
        "answer": "OSI session layer provides the protocols and means for two devices on the network to communicate with each other by holding a session. This layer is responsible for setting up the session, managing information exchange during the session, and tear-down process upon termination of the session.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "34) What is the maximum length allowed for a UTP cable?",
        "answer": "The maximum length of UTP cable is 90 to 100 meters.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) What is RIP?",
        "answer": "RIP stands for Routing Information Protocol. It is accessed by the routers to send data from one network to another.\nRIP is a dynamic protocol which is used to find the best route from source to the destination over a network by using the hop count algorithm.\nRouters use this protocol to exchange the network topology information.\nThis protocol can be used by small or medium-sized networks.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What do you understand by TCP/IP?",
        "answer": "TCP/IP is short for Transmission Control Protocol /Internet protocol. It is a set of protocol layers that is designed for exchanging data on different types of networks.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) What is netstat?",
        "answer": "The \"netstat\" is a command line utility program. It gives useful information about the current TCP/IP setting of a connection.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "38) What do you understand by ping command?",
        "answer": "The \"ping\" is a utility program that allows you to check the connectivity between the network devices. You can ping devices using its IP address or name.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "39) What is Sneakernet?",
        "answer": "Sneakernet is the earliest form of networking where the data is physically transported using removable media.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The processes on each machine that communicate at a given layer are called peer-peer process.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "41) What is a congested switch?",
        "answer": "A switch receives packets faster than the shared link. It can accommodate and stores in its memory, for an extended period of time, then the switch will eventually run out of buffer space, and some packets will have to be dropped. This state is called a congested state.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "42) What is multiplexing in networking?",
        "answer": "In Networking, multiplexing is the set of techniques that is used to allow the simultaneous transmission of multiple signals across a single data link.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "43) What are the advantages of address sharing?",
        "answer": "Address sharing provides security benefit instead of routing. That's because host PCs on the Internet can only see the public IP address of the external interface on the computer that provides address translation and not the private IP addresses on the internal network.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "44) What is RSA Algorithm?",
        "answer": "RSA is short for Rivest-Shamir-Adleman algorithm. It is mostly used for public key encryption.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "45) How many layers are in TCP/IP?",
        "answer": "There are basic 4 layers in TCP/IP:\nApplication Layer\nTransport Layer\nInternet Layer\nNetwork Layer",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "46) What is the difference between TCP/IP model and the OSI model?",
        "answer": "Following are the differences between the TCP/IP model and OSI model:\nTCP/IP model OSI model\nFull form of TCP is transmission control protocol. Full form of OSI is Open System Interconnection.\nTCP/IP has 4 layers. OSI has 7 layers.\nTCP/IP is more reliable than the OSI model. OSI model is less reliable as compared to the TCP/IP model.\nTCP/IP model uses horizontal approach. OSI model uses vertical approach.\nTCP/IP model uses both session and presentation layer in the application layer. OSI Reference model uses separate session and presentation layers.\nTCP/IP model developed the protocols first and then model. OSI model developed the model first and then protocols.\nIn Network layer, TCP/IP model supports only connectionless communication. In the Network layer, the OSI model supports both connection-oriented and connectionless communication.\nTCP/IP model is a protocol dependent. OSI model is a protocol independent.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    },
    {
        "question": "47) What is the difference between domain and workgroup?",
        "answer": "Workgroup Domain\nA workgroup is a peer-to-peer computer network. A domain is a Client/Server network.\nA Workgroup can consist of maximum 10 computers. A domain can consist up to 2000 computers.\nEvery user can manage the resources individually on their PCs. There is one administrator to administer the domain and its resources.\nAll the computers must be on the same local area network. The computer can be on any network or anywhere in the world.\nEach computer must be changed manually. Any change made to the computer will reflect the changes to all the computers.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "networking"
    }
]